<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Lswith&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://lswith.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lswith&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:00:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lswith.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Constitution of Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://lswith.io/posts/constitution-of-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lswith.io/posts/constitution-of-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;understanding-the-constitution-of-knowledge-by-jonathan-rauch&#34;&gt;Understanding the &amp;ldquo;Constitution of Knowledge&amp;rdquo; by Jonathan Rauch&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Jonathan Rauch&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brookings.edu/books/the-constitution-of-knowledge/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Constitution of Knowledge: A Defense of Truth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, he provides a compelling analysis of how societies can establish and sustain truth. Epistemic chaos, a central concern of the book, refers to a breakdown in shared understanding and agreement about what constitutes knowledge and truth. It occurs when misinformation and disinformation undermine trust in traditional sources of authority and expertise, leaving individuals and communities struggling to distinguish fact from fiction. This challenge is particularly pressing in an era of rampant misinformation and polarization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Teams Matter Over Individuals</title>
      <link>https://lswith.io/posts/teams-over-individuals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lswith.io/posts/teams-over-individuals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I started reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://teamtopologies.com/book&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Topologies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and quickly noticed that many of the key concepts in the book resonated deeply with my experiences at Dovetail. The most striking realization was the power of teams over individuals. This idea challenged some traditional notions of performance and productivity, highlighting that team structure and dynamics are far more important than individual brilliance. Reflecting on these concepts has helped me better understand some of the organizational issues we’ve encountered and provided a fresh lens for approaching potential solutions. This blog is the first in a series where I’ll explore the key learnings from &lt;em&gt;Team Topologies&lt;/em&gt; and share how they relate to my own experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure as an Enabler, Not a differentiator</title>
      <link>https://lswith.io/posts/infra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lswith.io/posts/infra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;infrastructure-as-an-enabler-not-a-differentiator&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure as an Enabler, Not a Differentiator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the fast-moving world of technology, it’s easy to be drawn to the latest and greatest infrastructure solutions. But for most companies, infrastructure shouldn’t be seen as the centerpiece of innovation. Instead, it’s a critical enabler—a foundation that supports product development, rather than a driver of differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;infrastructure-is-not-core-to-the-business&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure Is Not Core to the Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies succeed by delivering unique, customer-centric experiences. The core of this value lies in product innovation—the features, interfaces, and improvements that users interact with directly. Infrastructure, while essential for enabling that innovation, exists in the background. It’s the scaffolding that holds everything up, not the product that defines the customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Continous Delivery</title>
      <link>https://lswith.io/posts/continuous-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 09:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lswith.io/posts/continuous-delivery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;rethinking-continuous-delivery&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rethinking Continuous Delivery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous Delivery is the ability to consistently ship code multiple times a day to production. It enables fast and reliable delivery of features through automation of the release process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective release processes have a few essential qualities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speed&lt;/strong&gt;: Changes should be quick to get into production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplicity&lt;/strong&gt;: The process should be easy to understand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traceability&lt;/strong&gt;: It should be clear what was included in each release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A powerful approach to achieve these qualities is to center the release process around a build artifact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubeconf 2018: The Overview</title>
      <link>https://lswith.io/posts/kubeconf-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 17:23:30 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lswith.io/posts/kubeconf-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I attended KubeConf 2018 in Seattle a week ago.
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to distill the core concepts that I think are important from the conference into this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can categorize what the conference was trying to push into 5 concepts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observability is King&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do 1 Thing Well&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose Tools Appropriately&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everyone Needs to know Cloud Ops&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be Cloud Provider Agnostic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These aren&amp;rsquo;t new ideas but they were so prominent and spoken about in so many ways that they seemed
novel and obvious.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
